

🛘 +91 9829176214 | 🔀 grvsrm@outlook.com | 🌴 grvsrm.github.io | 🖸 grvsrm | 🛅 grvsrm | 💆 GRStats

Summary_

11+ years of experience in Automotive Manufacturing Industry in Advanced Manufacturing Analytics, Data Science, Industry 4.0, Factory Digitization, Plant Maintenance, Equipment Reliability and End to End Operation in Manufacturing. Functional and Configurational Exposure to SAP PM and RCM. Demonstrated ability to work across crossfunctional teams, independently and proactively.

Education

Indian School of Business Hyderabad, IN

ADVANCED MANAGEMENT PROGRAM IN BUSINESS ANALYTICS (AMPBA)

Jaipur, IN

Jaipur Engg. College & Research Centre, University of Rajasthan

BACHELORS OF ENGINEERING (BE)

2004-08

2018-19

Work Experience ___

FREELANCER Jaipur, IN

MANUFACTURING & ANALYTICS Apr. 2019 - Present

· Independent Assignments related to Manufacturing, Business Analytics, Teaching and Training

NEI LTD. Jaipur, IN

MANAGER - DIGITIZATION Apr. 2017 - Mar. 2019

- Managed Digitization Projects under Smart Factory Initiative with a Data Driven approach. Created PoCs and built Manufacturing Analytics use cases in manufacturing shop floor using advanced statistical and modern machine learning (supervised and unsupervised) methods
- · Converted Business Challenges into Analytical Problems and implement solutions independently. Responsible for bridging the gap between implementation partners and senior management in terms of requirement freezing and project management and KPI monitoring.
- Experienced in Data Mining & Predictive Modelling Causal, Time Series Forecasting, Simulation using Statistical Computer Language R/Python to draw inferences and conclusions from large data samples. Knowledge of Advance Probability and Statistical Concepts with their limitation and proper use.
- Experienced in Machine Learning Techniques for Prediction, Classification, Recommendation Systems and Clustering. Hands on experience of working on Data pre-processing, Feature Engineering, building Machine Learning Models and Ensembles, Hyperparameter tuning.

NEI LTD. Jaipur, IN

MANAGER - OPERATIONS & MAINTENANCE

Apr. 2013 - Mar. 2017

- Responsible for achieving /surpassing departmental KPIs such as Availability, MTTR, MTBF by using continuous improvement (TPM/TQM) tools and methodologies. executing improvement projects and new equipment installations, adherence to TPM standards., reduce downtime and maintenance cost, identification and execution of cost reduction projects.
- · Implemented Computerized maintenance management system (CMMS) SAP PM in the entire plant. Implemented RCM in entire plant, conducted failure mode effect analysis (FMEA), created equipment care strategies to make reliability predictions using root cause failure analysis (RCFA) techniques, FMEA & CBM techniques.

NEI LTD. Jaipur, IN

ENGINEER - OPERATIONS & MAINTENANCE

Aug. 2008 - Mar. 2013

• Full operational responsibility of electronic maintenance & planning of Industrial Equipment and Machinery, Robotics Automation, Industrial Automation, PLC Data Acquisition System. Overall responsible for department's planned and unplanned maintenance program which includes breakdown, preventive and predictive maintenance planning and execution.

Proiects_

VEHICLE DAMAGE DETECTION USING DEEP LEARNING

· Capstone project for an auto insurance startup to create a business workflow on how to detect damage using deep learning and predict the cost of repair beforehand to assist the insurance provider in minimizing the overall turnaround time. Won Best Capstone Award for successful PoC in ISB

NELLTD

• Digitized workforce visibility in the entire plant. Implemented for white- and blue-collar employees. Created the entire cyberinfrastructure and a real-time dashboard that updates the supervisors and managers on availability of skilled workforce available in shift and also provide suggestions based on man-machine skill matching to minimize losses occurring due to skilled workforce unavailability. Lead change management.

RCM IMPLEMENTATION Jaipur, IN

NEI LTD.

• Implemented Reliability Methodology in entire plant over across 1500 equipment. Drove entire project, ABC Analysis, conducted failure mode effect analysis (FMEA), performed asset criticalities, equipment cares strategies and maintenance policies to make reliability predictions for complete plant. Increased productivity by 21% on model lines. Lead change management.

SAP PM - CMMS IMPLEMENTATION

Jaipur,IN

NFLITD

 Designed SAP PM Process, As-Is To-Be Mapping, prepared master data for the Plant such as Functional Locations, Equipment & Sub-equipment, BOMs, Planner Groups, Work Centers, Measuring Points, Counters, Tasks Lists, Maintenance Packages, Maintenance Plans, Notifications, Break-down & Preventive Orders. Achieved 90% process digitization. Lead change management.



Data Science

DATA WRANGLING, FEATURE ENGINEERING, DATA VISUALIZATION, MACHINE LEARNING, STATISTICAL ANALYSIS

Languages & Applications

R, TABLEAU, SOME SQL & PYTHON

Manufacturing

SAP PM, RCM, TPM, PLC & CNC Programming, Project Management, Change Management

Awards & Recognition

Best Capstone Project Award

ISB

AWARDED FOR A SUCCESSFUL DEEP LEARNING POC WITH AN AUTO INSURANCE STARTUP

2019

CEO Circle Candidate

NEI LTD.

WAS RECOGNIZED AS FAST TRACK EMPLOYEE IN NEI LTD.

2017

Star Employee Award

NEI LTD.

AWARDED FOR EXHIBITING EXTRA-ORDINARY LEADERSHIP SKILLS AT WORKPLACE

2016